JIM BUITT

Park Ridge, IL 60068 914.356.0043

buitt@gmail.com

jim.buitt.com (personal website)

SUMMARY

Senior DevOps Engineer: extensive Linux system administration experience with expertise in programming, provisioning, and maintaining AWS cloud infrastructure, network components, and configuration management tools. Process improvement mindset through the development of efficient and effective software deployment and automation strategies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Shell Scripting • Python • Regular expressions • Perl • PHP • SQL •

HTML - JavaScript - CSS - JSON, YAML, & XML

Amazon Linux • Ubuntu & Debian • Apple macOS • RHEL & CentOS • Operating Systems:

Microsoft Windows 10

SSL/TLS certificates • SSH • KMS • Secrets Manager & SSM Security:

Parameter Store • VPN • OAUTH & SAML • JWT

Amazon RDS Aurora provisioned & serverless • MySQL • PostgreSQL Databases:

• MongoDB & DocumentDB • Redis & ElastiCache

Elastic Beanstalk • EC2 • S3 • Lambda • RDS • API Gateway • AWS Services: Cognito • VPC • CloudFront • IAM • SNS • SQS • WAF • ECR

Ansible, AWX, & Semaphore • CloudFormation • CodeBuild &

CodePipeline • Jenkins • GitLab • Docker • AWS X-Ray

Atlassian JIRA & Confluence • Cloudflare CDN • Slack • Microsoft SaaS:

Teams • Bitrise • Qualys CloudView • Microsoft AppCenter

New Relic • Nagios • CloudWatch • CloudTrail • Sensu Monitoring:

Apache & Nginx • Graylog • git • NFS & EFS • DNS & Route53 • Other Tools:

DHCP • KVM & LXC • Proxmox

Data Structures & Algorithms • Application Architecture • High **Technology Concepts:** Availability • RESTful APIs • Software Development Lifecycle

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASSURANT, CHICAGO, IL

DevOps Tools:

2019 - Present

Senior DevOps Engineer

- Lead Senior DevOps Engineer, for the Emerging Channels team, responsible for the B2B & B2C cloud infrastructure
- Provision & manage original and all new AWS infrastructure for company B2B and B2C mobile insurance applications
- Write and maintain CloudFormation templates for creating and managing AWS infrastructure
- Create & manage CI/CD process for developers and Code Pipelines in AWS to assist developer team in deploying code to DEV, QA, UAT, and PROD environments
- Utilize Bitrise to build iOS and Android apps & release to Apple and Google Play stores for PROD releases

Deleted: code

Deleted: Write

Deleted: for and

- Set up and monitor B2B and B2C applications using Nagios, New Relic, and CloudWatch and provided 24x7 DevOps support for applications; set up SOPs for the triage of PROD alerts
- Perform ongoing security audits of AWS infrastructure using Qualys CloudView with immediate issue mitigation and/or resolution
- Write and securely deploy Ansible playbooks to propagate application changes to servers
- Document and maintain all SOPs, HOWTOs, and release notes in Confluence

PUNCHKICK INTERACTIVE, CHICAGO, IL

2013 - 2019

Senior Linux System Administrator

- · Lead Systems Administrator, IT Manager, office Safety Warden, and Help Desk support for the organization
- Developed architecture, built out, maintained, and scaled application infrastructure for client projects
- Developed hosting agreements and service-level agreements for client hosting
- Installed and maintained operating system applications, security, and patches for 150+ company and client servers
- · Provisioned, configured, and maintained physical hardware & virtual servers for the internal network infrastructure and CI/CD
- Proactively maintained system integrity supporting change management, disaster recovery, and problem management
- Implemented and managed system backups, storage management, performance/tuning and capacity planning using customwritten software
- Created shell and Perl scripts, and use Ansible to automate system administration tasks
- Created LEMP-based websites and RESTful APIs to assist in administration of local tools & procedures for managing employee accounts, server inventory, server backups, and server/application monitoring
- Set-up/administered MDM for all company laptops (Apple) using Meraki Device Manager w/ Apple DEP & VPP
- · Automated employee onboarding and offboarding procedures, including integration with Snipe-IT inventory system

YESHIVA UNIVERSITY, INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SERVICES, New York, NY

2010 - 2013

Linux System Administrator

- Lead Linux Systems Administrator for SunGard Banner (160 servers)
- Planned, installed, maintained, and troubleshooted HP, NetApp, and ESX software and hardware
- Backup Engineer responsible for backup monitoring, troubleshooting, storage management, performance/tuning and capacity planning using Symantec NetBackup
- Evaluated, installed and configured support tools and third-party application software
- Wrote shell and Perl scripts to automate system administration tasks

SOUTHERN ILLINOIS UNIVERSITY, INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SERVICES - Carbondale & Edwardsville, IL 2000-2010

UNIX / Linux Administrator

- System administrator for Solaris and Linux systems (150+ servers)
- Installed, maintained, and supported Sun Enterprise servers; Intel servers and desktops, NetWorker Backup, Linux and Solaris firewalls, Web Mail, file servers, and authentication systems, and open-source software and utilities
- Created and maintained Perl and PHP scripts for web applications, UNIX systems, and data processing
- Managed server consolidation using VMWare products (Workstation and ESX/GSX/VMWare Server)

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

AWS ??? EXPECTED SUMMER 2022

SOUTHERN ILLINOIS UNIVERSITY AT CARBONDALE – Carbondale, IL

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; specialization in Programming Languages

1999